<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-19T07:17:13+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Buckist</title><subtitle>Best bucket list app on Google Play</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Health effects of friendship</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/friendship/health/2016/08/12/health/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Health effects of friendship" /><published>2016-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/friendship/health/2016/08/12/health</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/friendship/health/2016/08/12/health/">&lt;p&gt;Conventional wisdom suggests that good friendships enhance an individual’s sense of happiness and overall well-being. Indeed, a number of studies have found that strong social supports improve a woman’s prospects for good health and longevity. Conversely, loneliness and a lack of social supports have been linked to an increased risk of heart disease, viral infections, and cancer, as well as higher mortality rates overall. Two researchers have even termed friendship networks a “behavioral vaccine” that boosts both physical and mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1000&quot; alt=&quot;Man&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there is an impressive body of research linking friendship and health, the precise reasons for the connection remain unclear. Most of the studies in this area are large prospective studies that follow people over a period of time, and while there may be a correlation between the two variables (friendship and health status), researchers still do not know if there is a cause and effect relationship, such as the notion that good friendships actually improve health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1001&quot; alt=&quot;Thai&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of theories have attempted to explain this link. These theories have included that good friends encourage their friends to lead more healthy lifestyles; that good friends encourage their friends to seek help and access services when needed; that good friends enhance their friends’ coping skills in dealing with illness and other health problems; and that good friends actually affect physiological pathways that are protective of health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1002&quot; alt=&quot;lavender flowers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Conventional wisdom suggests that good friendships enhance an individual’s sense of happiness and overall well-being. Indeed, a number of studies have found that strong social supports improve a woman’s prospects for good health and longevity. Conversely, loneliness and a lack of social supports have been linked to an increased risk of heart disease, viral infections, and cancer, as well as higher mortality rates overall. Two researchers have even termed friendship networks a “behavioral vaccine” that boosts both physical and mental health.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://source.unsplash.com/collection/375719/2000x1322?a=.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Development Issues</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/friendship/psychology/2016/08/06/development-issues/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Development Issues" /><published>2016-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/friendship/psychology/2016/08/06/development-issues</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/friendship/psychology/2016/08/06/development-issues/">&lt;p&gt;Children with Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) may not have difficulty forming friendships, though they may have a hard time keeping them, due to impulsive behavior and hyperactivity. Children with Attention deficit disorder (ADD) may not have as much trouble keeping and maintaining friendships, though inattentiveness may complicate the processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1000&quot; alt=&quot;Cat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents of children with ADHD worry about their children’s ability to form long-lasting friendships. According to Edelman, “Making and keeping friends requires ‘hundreds’ of skills – talking, listening, sharing, being empathetic, and so on. These skills do not come naturally to children with ADD”. Difficulty listening to others also inhibits children with ADD or ADHD from forming good friendships. Children with these disorders can also drive away others by “blurting out unkind comments”. Their disruptive behavior can become too distracting to classmates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1001&quot; alt=&quot;Lady bugs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;autism&quot;&gt;Autism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children with autism spectrum disorders usually have some difficulty forming friendships. Certain symptoms of autism can interfere with the formation of interpersonal relations, such as a preference for routine actions, resistance to change, obsession with particular interests or rituals, and a lack of typical social skills. Children with autism spectrum disorders have been found to be more likely to be close friends of one person, rather than having groups of friends. Additionally, they are more likely to be close friends of other children with some sort of a disability.[26] A sense of parental attachment aids in the quality of friendships in children with autism spectrum disorders; a sense of attachment with one’s parents compensates for a lack of social skills that would usually inhibit friendships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1002&quot; alt=&quot;apricot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With time, moderation, and proper instruction, children with autism spectrum disorder are able to form friendships after realizing their own strengths and weaknesses. A study done by Frankel et al. showed that parental intervention and instruction plays an important role in such children developing friendships. Along with parental intervention, school professionals play an important role in teaching social skills and peer interaction. Paraprofessionals, specifically one-on-one aides and classroom aides, are often placed with children with autism spectrum disorders in order to facilitate friendships and guide the child in making and maintaining substantial friendships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1003&quot; alt=&quot;Marketing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although lessons and training may help peers of children with autism, bullying is still a major concern in social situations. According to Anahad O’Connor of The New York Times, bullying is most likely to occur against autistic children who have the most potential to live independently, such as those with Asperger syndrome. Such children are more at risk because they have as many of the rituals and lack of social skills as children with full autism, but they are more likely to be mainstreamed in school, since they are on the higher-functioning end of the autism spectrum. Children on the autism spectrum have more difficulty picking up on social cues of when they are maliciously being made fun of, so they do not always know when they are being bullied.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Children with Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) may not have difficulty forming friendships, though they may have a hard time keeping them, due to impulsive behavior and hyperactivity. Children with Attention deficit disorder (ADD) may not have as much trouble keeping and maintaining friendships, though inattentiveness may complicate the processes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://source.unsplash.com/collection/375719/2000x1322?a=.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Life cycle of friendships</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/friendship/2016/08/02/life-cycle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life cycle of friendships" /><published>2016-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/friendship/2016/08/02/life-cycle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/friendship/2016/08/02/life-cycle/">&lt;p&gt;Three significant factors make the formation of a friendship possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proximity – nearness or having a place or places to interact&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeated, unplanned interactions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A setting that encourages people to confide in each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1000&quot; alt=&quot;Coins&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dissolution&quot;&gt;Dissolution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friendships end for many different reasons. Sometimes friends move away from each other and the relationship wanes due to the distance. Digital technology has however made geographic distance less of an obstacle to maintaining a friendship. Sometimes divorce causes an end to friendships, as people drop one or both of the divorcing people. For young people, friendships may end as a result of acceptance into new social groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1001&quot; alt=&quot;American River&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friendships may end by fading quietly away or may end suddenly. How and whether to talk about the end of a friendship is a matter of etiquette that depends on the circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Three significant factors make the formation of a friendship possible:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://source.unsplash.com/collection/375719/2000x1322?a=.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Psychology of friendship</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/friendship/science/2016/07/28/psychology-of-friendship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Psychology of friendship" /><published>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/friendship/science/2016/07/28/psychology-of-friendship</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/friendship/science/2016/07/28/psychology-of-friendship/">&lt;p&gt;In the typical sequence of an individual’s emotional development, friendships come after parental bonding and before pair bonding. In the intervening period between the end of early childhood and the onset of full adulthood, friendships are often the most important relationships in the emotional life of the adolescent, and are often more intense than relationships later in life. The absence of friends can be emotionally damaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1000&quot; alt=&quot;Fair&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evolution&quot;&gt;Evolution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evolutionary psychology approach to human development has led to the theory of Dunbar’s number, proposed by British anthropologist Robin Dunbar. He theorized that there is a limit of approximately 150 people with whom a human can maintain stable social relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;childhood&quot;&gt;Childhood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In childhood, friendships are often based on the sharing of toys, and the enjoyment received from performing activities together. These friendships are maintained through affection, sharing, and creative playtime. While sharing is difficult for children at this age, they are more likely to share with someone they consider to be a friend. As children mature, they become less individualized and are more aware of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1001&quot; alt=&quot;Gleise&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They begin to see their friends’ points of view, and enjoy playing in groups. They also experience peer rejection as they move through the middle childhood years. Establishing good friendships at a young age helps a child to be better acclimated in society later on in their life. In a 1975 study, Bigelow and La Gaipa found that expectations for a “best friend” become increasingly complex as a child gets older. The study investigated such criteria in a sample of 480 children between the ages of six and fourteen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their findings highlighted three stages of development in friendship expectations. In the first stage, children emphasized shared activities and the importance of geographical closeness. In the second, they emphasized sharing, loyalty, and commitment. In the final stage, they increasingly desired similar attitudes, values, and interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prize-friendships&quot;&gt;Prize friendships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Berndt, children prize friendships that are high in pro-social behavior, intimacy, and other positive features; they are troubled by friendships that are high in conflict, dominance, rivalry, and other negative features. High-quality friendships have often been assumed to have positive effects on many aspects of children’s social development. Perceived benefits from such friendships include enhanced social success, but they apparently do not include an effect on children’s general self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous studies with adults suggest that friendships and other supportive relationships do enhance self-esteem. Other potential benefits of friendship include the opportunity to learn about empathy and problem solving. Coaching from parents can be useful in helping children to make friends. Eileen Kennedy-Moore describes three key ingredients of children’s friendship formation: (1) openness, (2) similarity, and (3) shared fun. Parents can also help children understand social guidelines they haven’t learned on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing from research by Robert Selman and others, Kennedy-Moore outlines developmental stages in children’s friendship, reflecting an increasing capacity to understand others’ perspectives: “I Want It My Way”, “What’s In It For Me?”, “By the Rules”, “Caring and Sharing”, and “Friends Through Thick and Thin.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">In the typical sequence of an individual’s emotional development, friendships come after parental bonding and before pair bonding. In the intervening period between the end of early childhood and the onset of full adulthood, friendships are often the most important relationships in the emotional life of the adolescent, and are often more intense than relationships later in life. The absence of friends can be emotionally damaging.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://source.unsplash.com/collection/375719/2000x1322?a=.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What is a friend?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/friends/2016/07/20/what-is-a-friend/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is a friend?" /><published>2016-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/friends/2016/07/20/what-is-a-friend</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/friends/2016/07/20/what-is-a-friend/">&lt;p&gt;Friendship is a relationship of mutual affection between people. Friendship is a stronger form of interpersonal bond than an association. Friendship has been studied in academic fields such as sociology, social psychology, anthropology, and philosophy. Various academic theories of friendship have been proposed, including social exchange theory, equity theory, relational dialectics, and attachment styles. A World Happiness Database study found that people with close friendships are happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1000&quot; alt=&quot;Checkmate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;forms-of-friendship&quot;&gt;Forms of friendship&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there are many forms of friendship, some of which may vary from place to place, certain characteristics are present in many types of bond. Such characteristics include affection, sympathy, empathy, honesty, altruism, mutual understanding, and compassion, enjoyment of each other’s company, trust, and the ability to be oneself, express one’s feelings, and make mistakes without fear of judgment from the friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there is no practical limit on what types of people can form a friendship, friends tend to share common backgrounds, occupations, or interests and have similar demographics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/random/1500x1001&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberries&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Friendship is a relationship of mutual affection between people. Friendship is a stronger form of interpersonal bond than an association. Friendship has been studied in academic fields such as sociology, social psychology, anthropology, and philosophy. Various academic theories of friendship have been proposed, including social exchange theory, equity theory, relational dialectics, and attachment styles. A World Happiness Database study found that people with close friendships are happier.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://source.unsplash.com/collection/375719/2000x1322?a=.png" /></entry></feed>